♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson and
his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in
an endless chase ♪
♪ Pursued by a woman
who's name is Pearl ♪
♪ An evil gal who wants
to rule the world ♪
♪ She threw a few
things in her purse ♪
♪ And in her rocket ship ♪
♪ She hunts him all
across the universe ♪
♪ I'll get you ♪
♪ I'm send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And I'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cam bot ♪
♪ You're on ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Oh my stars ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ Check me out ♪
♪ Crow ♪
I'm different
♪ If you wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself ♪
♪ Its just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(doors whirring and clanking)
- Ladies and Gypsy,
Michael Nelson
is lord of the dance.
- Did the other one die?
- No.
Anyway, Michael Nelson
is lord of the dance.
- Oh okay.
- Three, four.
(humming)
(rapid drum music)
- Oh.
Yay.
Well.
There's this sink I
need to take a look out.
So I'll just be.
- Three, four.
(humming)
(rapid drum music)
- Oh my.
Oh, okay.
We'll be right back.
- Three, four.
(humming)
(rapid drum music)
(upbeat music)
- Um, Mike, its over, huh?
- Hey, lord of the pants,
can you tear yourself away
from yourself for a minute?
We got someone calling
from the planet.
- Hello?
- Oh hello, Mike.
- I should say hello Mike.
- Oh I don't think so.
Hello, Mike.
- Hello, Mike.
- Let me say it.
- Shut up.
(overlapping arguing)
- Hey what the Sam
Hill is going on?
Where's Mrs. F?
- Pain.
Do you mind terribly,
if I explain?
- Oh be my guest.
You're not in charge.
He's not in charge.
- Mike, Pearl is driving those
horrid little children home
and Bobo here, who by the
way is not at all smelly
or riddled with infection.
Simply cannot accept the
fact that I am in charge.
- You are not.
- I am, too.
Read the note.
It says while I'm away the
brain guy is in charge.
- It does not.
Give me that note.
It says you're a dodo head.
- I'm a dodo head?
Of all the unmitigated
gall, you're the dodo head.
- You're the dodo head.
- No you're the dodo head.
You're the dodo.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Not that I care, but you guys
are gonna have to figure out
a way to get along
until she gets back.
Is there something you can
do where nobody's in charge?
- Well she did leave
us this list of tasks.
Perhaps we could
divide those up.
- Fine, you're not in charge.
He's not in charge.
- Oh a great many
of these tasks seem
to pertain to you, Bobo.
- Well I'm very delicate.
- Each morning begins
with a tick bath for Bobo
then while he is still
groggy, push worm medicine
down his throat.
- I have worms.
- Then mash 64 bananas
by hand, cover with honey
and sprinkle with termites.
- I won't eat them
any other way.
- Then apply a generous
portion of ointment
to his, oh no!
- You have to.
- No.
Mike, I can tolerate
this ape no more.
I appeal to you as a
somewhat higher being,
come down here and, well
just come down here.
Ha, there you are.
Now see, he wants me to
apply ointment to his, see.
- Oh come on, its not so bad.
There are worse places
to apply ointment.
- Okay, I'll tell
you what I see.
I see here that there are
a lot of underlying issues
and I don't think we can move
on until we get past those.
Brain Guy, why don't you start?
- Okay.
Its like ever since
I met these two,
the whole world revolves
around Bobo's hygiene.
Its endless supply of tick
baths and flea powderings
and swollen things.
- You know, Mike,
sometimes I get the feeling
he doesn't even care
about my hygiene.
- And frankly his daily
cleaning rituals disgust me.
- At least with
me they get done.
- What are you implying?
- I'm implying B.O!
- B.O?
That's absurd.
I don't even have a body.
- Now, Brain Guy, I think
we have to get past that.
Tell you what, as a gesture,
why don't you smell yourself?
- No.
- Please in the interest
of peace smell yourself.
- Oh very well.
Oh my god, I do stink.
Oh I'm so sorry.
This is embarrassing.
- See this is a
real breakthrough
and I think its a
beautiful moment.
I'll tell you what, why
don't you grab your brain,
and head up to the satellite
and watch that movie
of yours and think about
this moment, all right?
- Thank you, thank you, Mike.
Its called Jack
Frost, by the way,
its a Russian Finnish
co production.
So I think I will
enjoy it immensely.
Thank you, thank you.
- Watch your head now.
(laughing)
Stinky Brain Guy.
- Oh you do smell.
- Really?
- We got movie sign.
- We got movie sign!
Wait a minute, what am I?
Nelson, get up here!
(doors clanking and whirring)
- [Tom] Oh good one, Mike.
- Yeah, I almost got
the Brain Guy in here.
- [Tom] Could eat no frost.
- Oh (sneezes).
- [Mike] Names are all
Russian for Alan Smithee.
(snoring)
- Hey, Tom Petty.
- [Tom] Its all
right if you love me.
(fly buzzing)
- [Mike] Hey listen, its
Spock in really fast motion.
(sneeze)
- Ah, Roseanne.
- [Tom] My east German
(speaks German) has a cold.
- Hey come on old
man, still yourself.
- [Mike] Come on, I
want to reproduce again.
- The mosquitoes are
stinging my darling little
Marfusha and can't sleep.
- Oh now listen.
Oh all right, I
didn't say a word.
- Great, I'll bet Pippi
Longstockings in this.
- [Mike] Pretend
your a koala bear
and eat these eucalyptus leaves.
(groaning)
- [Tom] Kielbasa belch.
- Arsenic sucker,
that should do it.
(humming)
- [Mike] Is this a
biopic of Holy Hobby?
- [Tom] The story of a
hundred year old couple
who give birth to
a giant infant.
(groaning)
- Don't wave Grandma's
funk over here, please.
- [Mike] I'm a domestic goddess.
- What are you doing
there, Nastika?
- Just knitting
Marfusha's new stocking.
- Knitting huh?
- [Tom] Why is the
coatrack on fire?
- Well you told me to knit
some stockings before.
- Be quiet.
- All you Novitiates
are trouble.
- I told you to knit
but I never told you
to click your needles
like that, did I?
Before you know, you'll
wake my little darling.
- Can she really hear
that through those walls?
- She certainly can.
(all shout)
You work by day
like a young male
so you can sleep by night.
(all groan)
But darling, little
Marfusha cannot be in there.
She must not be, she
has to rest by day
so by night, the
slightest noise wakes her.
- [Mike] Um (mumbles).
- Lets go clean some fish.
- Here's a place where
you can knit, Nastenka,
and you won't wake my
darling little Marfusha.
The moon is out,
there's plenty of light.
- [Mike] Chernobyl's
on fire, its great.
- Its peaceful and
its nice and cool.
(dog barks)
- [Tom] Eat it, Grandma.
- Be quiet.
- [Crow] Back into
Harpo's chest.
- You give me so much work.
- [Mike] This is the factory
where they make Beanie Babies.
- [Tom] Jack Klugman.
- Stocking must be finished
by the time the rooster crows,
do you hear me?
- [Tom] Okay, mom, thanks.
- Otherwise, my
precious little girl,
I will tear your braid off.
- And this father many
times you beat me.
O is for the other
(soft tense music)
(shushes)
- [Mike] Oh their
other puppy, he's cute.
- [Tom] I got to sneak down
to the convenience store
and go to the bathroom.
- [Mike] I wish she'd take
that mouse out of her mouth.
- [Tom] Don't come
around here no more.
- [Mike] You keep knitting
and knitting and knitting.
- Ah, Penny Marshall
was an adorable child.
- [Tom] You want
a stinking sock?
I'll knit you a stinking sock,
here's your stinking sock.
- Oh there's are fly specks.
They've been aiming.
- [Mike] She's so
hideous when she sleeps.
- [Tom] Surge!
- Mm, liver on a stick.
- [Mike] Danny Bonaduce
is Sleeping Beauty.
- With god as my witness,
I'll never go hungry again.
- [Mike] So the first plot
point involves knitting socks.
I think we're in for
a quite a ride, guys.
- You bet.
- [Tom] Boy, I say boy.
(whimsical music)
- Down, Tabusha.
- Its Rex, ma'am.
- Give me a little time,
please, pretty rooster.
Please, I've only
got one row to knit.
(squawking)
- [Rooster] Roosters
can only obey the sun.
You'll have to ask rosy dawn.
- [Mike] Or you could talk to
my supervisor if you'd like.
- [Tom] New Claritin-D.
- Wow, the suns really booking.
- [Tom] Chickens, lock
up your daughters.
I'm on the prowl.
- [Mike] Hey, hey
honey, where you going?
You want to come in?
- Oh, she's mooning us.
- Have mercy, rosy
fingered dawn,
have mercy on me, oh
rising golden sun.
- [Tom] And you are?
- Wait till I'm done
knitting these stockings.
Otherwise I'll be
punished severely.
Stepmother said she
would tear off my braid.
- [Mike] This is the sun.
Your call is very
important to us
but due to unusually
high call volume.
- [Tom] Oh the worlds
thrown into chaos,
earthquakes, floods,
but that's fine.
You knit your sock.
(soft classical music)
- Thank you, rosy fingered dawn.
- [Mike] Someday you'll
return the favor.
- Now I gotta keep
stirring the sauce, deliver
these guns to Jimmy.
- [Tom] I heard that.
- My darling bird
with the golden call.
I'm so happy, my pretty one.
Thank you, it's done.
- [Mike] Yeah sure.
Do you know any foxy hens?
Hey?
- See, I'm finished.
- You lazy girl, have
you finished yet?
- Look.
- So you did it on time.
Why, you wicked little viper,
you wicked little witch.
I'll give you much
harder work next time.
In the meantime, go
feed the chickens,
water the cattle's, flip the
water and sweep the yard.
- You know, Mike, I
think I just don't like
evil Russo-Finnish grandmas.
- [Tom] Take this
job and shove it.
- Tabusha.
(crowing)
- [Mike] How bout a little
sugar for the rooster?
- This is a test of the
emergency broadcast chicken.
- [Tom] Peter must be walking
around denying everybody
this morning.
- [Narrator] On the very same
morning of the very same day.
(clearing throat)
- [Mike] Morning.
- [Tom] Morning.
- Hey watch it.
- [Mike] Well the chores
are done for the day.
- [Tom] Think I'll go knack
off a bottle of Finlandia.
- [Mike] He's got
June Allison hair.
- Ivan, my son.
- Yes, mama, what is it now?
- Bring these bags
to be recycled.
- You must take care.
- Don't worry.
- You mustn't forget
your mother, Ivan.
- [Ivan] Don't worry.
- [Tom] Or me, Jerry Quarry.
- You mustn't harm the weak.
- [Ivan] Don't worry.
- Honor those who are old.
- [Ivan ] Don't worry.
- [Mike] Just going
to get a paper.
- And I even made
him Lunchables.
- [Group] We will rob them.
We won't rob them.
- [Tom] Damn, hobbits.
- [Group] We will eat them.
We won't eat them.
- [Mike] The Ozark
Mountain Daredevils
plan their next album.
- [Group] We'll be beaten.
- Oh sorry, that was me.
- [Group] We will rob them.
We won't rob them.
We will eat them.
We won't eat them.
- [Mike] Hey wake
up and go to sleep.
(shouting)
- [Tom] Oh look.
- [Group] We will rob them.
- That's their outhouse.
- [Group] We will eat them.
- [Tom] Fin blight
is bad this year.
(grunting)
- [Mike] Oh wait,
today its cluck cluck.
(man whistling)
- I lost a Titleist
three down here.
Anyone?
- [Mike] This is the early
version of Snow White,
called Snow White and the
one normal sized person.
- [Tom] Oh what a beautiful
(mock foreign language)
oh what a beautiful
- [Mike] A wandering
youth minister.
- Halt!
Halt!
- [Tom] Get a haircut, hippie.
- You're captured.
- The human schnauzer.
- And now, young man,
we're going to rob you.
- Do you mean that?
- Yes, we do.
(barking)
- All right, rob me.
- [Tom] I'll strip
if you want me to.
(overlapping shouting)
- You know, I think
I'd rather be hog piled
by actual hogs.
(upbeat music)
- [Mike] Wow, that's the
biggest clove I've ever seen.
(men clamoring)
- [Tom] Uh oh.
He's ignoring his mom's advice.
Don't throw cudgels in the air.
- All right, did somebody
drop some femurs over here?
- [Tom] I think he's missed
the point of juggling.
- They're frantically
hoping he has a louse comb.
- [Mike] He's got Playboys!
- [Tom] I'm gonna keep doing
this until someone notices me.
- Fins celebrate the new year
by hurling giant beef sticks
high into the air.
- [Mike] Wow, listen to
the bass on those cudgels.
- You didn't tell us
you were mythical.
- Why don't those
clubs come down again?
- Just wait my eager
little bandits.
They'll come down next winter.
- Next winter?
- That's right.
- [Tom] Now quit bouncing
and behaving, boy.
(whistling)
- Next winter, he says.
- Did you see that man?
That takes muscle.
He's strong all right.
- Very strong.
(barking)
- That's odd.
- The Giotto dwarfs.
- [Narrator] How long
did our young hero, Ivan,
wander over hill and dale?
Frankly, we have no idea.
- [Tom] Who's talking?
- [Narrator] The fact
remains that Ivan
eventually reached far
away and unknown lands.
- [Mike] And the cudgels
came down way earlier
than next winter and
maimed several children.
- Ivan.
- I have a new church hat.
- [Tom] Yeah I've eaten
those and had this happen.
- Ivan Lushka.
- [Mike] So what does a
mushroom eat for hallucinations?
- I think they lick toads.
- Ivan Lushka.
- [Tom] My hair
is talking to me.
(whimsical music)
- [Mike] Oh I always pick
that little guy off my pizza.
- Ivan Lushka, try
me on a plaza burger.
- [Tom] Are you
freaking out yet?
- All right, who's playing
hide and seek with me now?
- [Mike] Hey doll, derry
doll, Tom Bombadillo.
- You?
- Cute outfit.
- Yes.
- Are you a
sorcerer, granddaddy?
- I dabble in sorcery a
little but the truth is
that I get bored.
- You get bored?
- I get bored.
- [Mike] Do you get bored?
- Come on, play with me.
Let's play hide
and seek together.
- With you?
Play hide and seek?
- Yes.
- You're joking.
I'd catch you in no time.
- Think so?
- Yes, I think so.
- If you catch me, I'll
give you a well bent bow
and some nice straight arrows.
Is that a bargain?
- [Ivan] Its a bargain,
father mushroom.
- I thought Jerry Garcia
was father mushroom.
- [Mike] Finally,
I have a boyfriend.
- [Tom] I'm Hans.
Oh, forget it.
- I'm gonna go hunt for your
cousin, corn smut, instead.
(whimsical music)
- [Mike] You twisted
little wood ear.
I'm gonna.
- [Tom] Mince mince mince mince.
- [Mike] Frodo gets drunk and
screws with his neighbors.
(goofy humming)
- [Tom] Goofy guy.
Goofy guy.
Goofy funny wacky scene.
Funny guy.
Goofy guy.
Funny goofy, funny see.
(laughs)
Goofy, funny, see.
- Ivan Lushka.
- If disappearing
elf hide and seek
were in the Olympics, Finland
would be in great shape.
(tense classical music)
- [Mike] I gotta
go toss a cudgel.
- [Tom] Bella Abzug.
- The movie that dares
to ask the question
will he find the dwarf?
- [Mike] If I catch you,
you're in my omelet so fast.
- Can't catch me, can't
catch me, can't catch me.
- [Tom] He's so mature.
- You're going
down, mushroom boy.
You mincing little fungus.
- Well you didn't catch me.
- All right, you win.
- Good boy, Ivan.
Since you admit you lost.
I'm going to give you
the things I promised.
- [Mike] Then we
shall drink tranya.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Wow, Dad, its a daisy.
- Its a miracle.
- Without miracles
where would we be?
- Oh you're a real magician.
- Now start running, shroom.
- [Mike] Wow, it barely works.
- Ivan.
- Yes?
- Come back here.
- Why?
- You have forgotten the
most important thing, Ivan.
- And what have I forgotten?
- You forgot to say thank
you to a very old man.
You should bow your
head down to the ground.
- Those who bow run the
risk of losing their head.
- Ivan.
- The bear will bow before
you if you like, not Ivan.
- Then so be it.
- [Tom] Soviet.
- Things will come
to pass as you say.
- [Tom] Mike get that,
huh, its a commie movie.
- They will bow before
me down to the ground
but it is your back
that will bend.
- We now end our
elf broadcast day.
- [Mike] Yeah, now he's
haunted by other vegetables
he didn't eat as a child.
- He's pursued by a demonic
little Brussels sprout.
- (mumbles) lima bean.
(tense classical music)
- [Mike] Yeah, that
looks like Crazy Horse.
- [Tom] Okay movie, we can
wait as long as you can.
Come on.
- Heckle and Jeckle in
the ten commandments.
- [Mike] Its a fish boil recipe.
- [Ivan] Find the
feather in the field
and throw it to the winds.
If you follow that feather,
you will find your destiny.
- Touch any part of this
rock for more information.
- [Mike] Great, still don't
know where the men's room is.
(tense classical music)
- Am I Kirock?
- [Tom] When he
takes him to meet him
he should feather his hair.
- [Mike] What is that?
Spaceships landing?
(mystical whirring)
- Hey Ron, I'm
looking at your butt.
(laughs)
- [Tom] No I meant
the loons, kill them.
- Oh that's always nice.
Good work.
- [Mike] It was a good ride.
- [Tom] Thanks for the feather,
you can go back up now.
- I just read something about
feathers, what was that?
(soft classical music)
- [Tom] Now go find Forest
Gump, stick him in the eye
and kill him.
- There's a feather craft
approaching, Captain.
- [Mike] Its looking for a
Dunkin Heinz cake to slice.
(mock motorcycle noises)
- Ah, he's a worthy
adversary, that feather is.
- [Mike] Oh my destiny
sucks, its a swamp.
- [Tom] Hey the Peterson's
put their boat out.
(singing in foreign language)
- [Mike] Hildegard
of Bingen, unplugged.
(singing in foreign language)
- I have terminal
enchantment right now.
- [Mike] I want to be the
girl with the most cake.
(mock nasally singing)
- I think her adorablity
is crashing in on itself.
- [Mike] Oh, oh please
ma'am, my ears are bleeding.
- [Tom] She's a castrati.
- Retaining a lot of water.
- [Mike] The minute you
walked in the joint.
- [Tom] I think she's
headed for the vodka well.
- That's a girl, I
thought I was a girl.
(doors clanking and whirring)
Great news, Mike.
Through the magic of the
Hex field view screen
I got an expert to clarify
some of the questions
raised by today's movie.
- Oh really, great.
- Yeah thanks to me
digging into your wallet
I was able to raise
the money to bring us
the distinguished Russian
poet, author, and professor.
- Pushkin?
- Solzhenitsyn?
- Yakov Smirnoff.
Mr. Smirnoff, thank
you for taking time
from your busy schedule to
answer some of our questions.
- No problem.
- Now, Mr. Smirnoff, let
me cite Joseph Campbell
who says that each culture
establishes archetypes
which embody that
particular culture.
How does that apply in
the film Jack Frost?
- Well you see, in your country
you wait in line at bank.
In our country, we
wait in line for bread.
(laughter)
- Oh well uh.
Yeah, well how does that relate
to the diminishment
of Russo-Finnish ties?
- In your country,
the man shave.
In my country, we wish
the women would shave.
(laughter)
- Well, well.
Naturally that speaks to
the political structure
that attempted to suppress
such cultural expression.
Right?
- In your country, you
see movie The Rock.
In our country, we
break rock in gulag.
- All right, Smirnoff!
I want my 25,000 dollar
lecture fee back.
- 25,000...
- Its okay, Mike, I put
it on your credit card.
There's a lot of room on it.
- In your country--
- Oh shut up!
- We'll be right back.
- You know you can kiss that
cheese tray behind, pal.
- But I have contract.
- Yeah you have contract.
I'll tell you what you
can do with your contract.
(upbeat music)
Yakoff, what a ripoff.
- [Mike] Yeah.
- [Tom] I'm gonna
make some hooch.
- You know making her empty
the river is just busy work.
- [Mike] And it runs
back down the hill.
- [Tom] Oh I don't mean to
push but are my socks done yet?
- How do you do, my
pretty little maid?
- Oh There's a bull
snake on her neck.
- You're the prettiest
little thing I've ever seen.
Don't be afraid of me.
Look at me, my pretty one.
Look at me, look
at me all you like.
Now.
- [Mike] Do I look
like Simon Le Bond?
- [Ivan] Am I not
worth looking at?
- I have no time to speak
to you, I've got to work.
- [Tom] I'm a welder by
day and a dancer by night.
- What are you doing?
- I'm watering this old stump.
- How long will you
go on watering it?
- I mean how dumb are you?
- I'll water it until
flowers start to bloom on it.
- Flowers?
- My stepmother told me to.
- You must have a very
wicked stepmother.
- [Mike] Yeah, standard issue.
- Stepmothers are stepmothers.
- What's your name?
- [Tom] What a conniving face.
- Well, my name is Nastia.
- Nastia?
- Ms. Jackson if you're nasty.
- That's not what
everybody calls me.
- [Mike] She looks like a gray.
- My father calls me Nastenka.
- Nastenka.
- [Tom] It means stump waterer.
- My sister says Nastika.
Stepmother calls me Viper.
- Which is totally bogus.
- And sometimes little witch.
- Nastenka.
Darling, will you marry me?
- [Tom] I'm nine.
- You're in a terrible hurry.
- Well I'm not crippled
or cross eyed, am I?
- I know you're not.
- [Mike] But what am I?
- I don't think we would ever
make a good couple, though.
- What do you mean?
- Why you're a braggart.
I'm not.
- So you think I'm a braggart?
I'll have you know I
really can do everything.
- Oh?
- Yes, I'm a very good plowman,
nobody can outfight me,
I'm a good worker, a
fisherman, and a dancer,
and a hunter,
here, I'll show you.
- A dancer I buy.
- I'll shoot that bear
down with only one arrow.
- No don't do
that, she has cubs.
- Cubs?
Well what if she--
- Chapa, Chapa, Chapa!
- [Tom] I'm piddling.
(barking)
(shouting)
- [Mike] Bien, bien, bien.
- Paul Williams.
- Nastia.
- [Tom] It was her
bucket full of Rogaine.
- [Ivan] What's the matter?
- Am I un-bear-able?
- Nastia.
Nastenka.
- [Mike] Oh I'm bear intolerant.
- [Tom] Oh, salmon breath.
- Let me get you some grubs.
- [Mike] Can you
look at your lips
and tell me if you're breathing?
- She's alive.
- [Tom] Oh no, I lost my hat.
(growling)
- Damn it, puck, this
time you've gone too far.
- What did you do to me?
What have you done, you witch!
- [Tom] Mommy.
(Sobs)
I've got to go find
a pic-a-nic basket.
- Ivan Lushka.
- We have to
register at Club Wed!
- I swear I didn't
do anything to you.
- I curse you!
I curse you forever!
You witch!
(growling)
- [Mike] Hey you can always
get a job as sports mascot.
- [Tom] Tonight on a very
special Grizzly Adams.
- Dana Kukin.
- [Mike] Every time I meet a
man he's either gay or a bear.
- [Tom] A tribute to
Eurasian mill foil.
- With retsyn.
Again with retsyn.
Retsyn.
The KGB has her
under surveillance.
- [Tom] Gross.
- [Mike] I should
have married him.
I'm getting so old.
(humming)
- Well she shouldn't cry,
there's always Jerry Lee Lewis,
or Jerry Seinfeld,
or Ben Kingsley.
- [Mike] Hello, hello?
Russo-Finnish co-production?
- Give me some french
fried potaters.
- I killed you with an arrow
and you ruined me
with a feather.
- [Mike] Its funny when
you think about it.
- [Tom] You know back when they
didn't know about costuming
they actually had to find
a half man half bear.
- I've got to learn how to
ride a tricycle in a hurry.
- [Mike] Warning,
hang food in trees.
Hey.
- Like a bear, you wouldn't
have the head of a bear.
- [Tom] Forgot to
read the fine runes.
- [Mike] Sort of a bloated mouth
breathing bear, but a bear.
- Ivan, Ivan.
With the head of a bear.
- [Crow] Yeah bit me, wok head.
- Forgive me, father
mushroom, forgive me, please.
- You see, Ivan, things
have come to pass
as you said, the bear bows
his head to the ground
but its your back that is bent.
- Oh teach me how
to be reasonable
and first of all tell me
exactly what I should do
so that I may be a man again.
- All right, listen.
Vagabond with the
head of a bear.
Just look at yourself and ask.
- [Tom] Do I crap in the woods?
- How did you live?
You see, you spent all
of your time boasting
to everybody, you
loved yourself.
You loved only yourself.
You offended everyone else.
- Heed these words, Mike.
- [Mike] Okay.
- You hurt her feelings.
- I hurt her feelings?
- You've never done
a good thing, Ivan.
Now here's my answer.
Here's my advice to you.
- Shave.
- Although, I am wondering
whether you can understand it.
- Of course I understand.
- [Tom] I'm a
great understander.
- I'll just go and
do a good deed.
When I've done a good deed,
I'll get my own head back.
- Ivan.
Ivan!
- [Mike] You can make a
lot of money wrestling.
- You haven't
understood anything.
- [Tom] Oh I didn't know
there that many landmines
left in Narnia.
(upbeat music)
- Ah but I like it, too.
- Hello, tell me what good
deeds can I do for you?
(screaming)
- [Mike] Well you could stop
crapping on our playground
for one.
- Stop!
Wait.
(screaming)
Don't run away.
- [Tom] He's outrunning a
really slow quarter horse
at this point.
- Wait, I want to do
a good deed for you.
Wait.
Wait!
- When animals attack.
- [Mike] Now it will
go into slow motion
and you'll hear Barbers
Adagio for strings
as he tears them apart.
- [Tom] And he falls
right on bear plop.
- Um, Ricola?
Muxinex?
- [Mike] Charlie was
close, I could feel it.
- [Tom] Oh there's my wallet.
- As the Easter egg hunt
goes into its 48th week.
(growling)
- [Mike] Friend good.
- [Tom] Ah the perfect
speaker stand, finally.
- And here's that footstool
I've always wanted.
- [Mike] Aw, you know?
(all cooing)
I'll take this back to the
lab, see if its edible or not.
- [Tom] Hurry, the DNR's coming.
Load up the truck
and get out of here.
(growls)
(screaming)
- Icky boys, ew.
- [Mike] Delayed
reaction syndrome.
(shouting)
- There's a bear there.
- [Tom] Quick, there's
a sale on babushkas
at Bloomingdale-skis.
(laughs)
- Chernobyl's exploding again.
Let's go watch.
- [Tom] I could watch this
scene play out all day.
Well.
- [Mike] How not to be seen.
(soft classical music)
- So what, are we looking
for Waldo here or what?
- [Tom] Antony, Antony!
- [Mike] Its prince
spaghetti today here
in the Italian north
end of the swamp.
- Good morning, little flowers,
little flowers on the stump.
- Yeah, you got the money?
- [Mike] Oh just make
yourself at home.
- Every single day
I come to see you.
Every single day I
come to talk to you.
I hope that I'm
not bothering you.
- [Tom] Have a seat
in the waiting room,
one of our flowers will
be with you in a moment.
- Its all right?
- its okay.
You in, I'm in love with you.
- Tell me, little flowers.
Is Ivan still living today?
- [Tom] Uh definitely, yes.
- I don't know?
- Yeah, uh, I don't know.
Come back tomorrow.
- [Mike] You want to take this?
- He's alive?
- We didn't say that.
- He must be angry
with me, I suppose.
- [Tom] I need to check with
our flowers on the street.
- You mean he's not?
- [Mike] Hey look, I'm just
asking for straight answers.
Don't bust my chops, man.
- Now tell me,
will we ever meet?
- Our lawyers have
advised us not to comment.
- [Tom] Ew, what
am I kneeling in?
- Yes, look for the
answer in the algae.
- [Mike] From the land
of sky blue waters.
(growling)
- [Tom] I mean where
else are you gonna do it
but in the woods?
- Charity, dear little sisters,
dear little brothers, charity.
Dear little sisters, dear
little brothers, charity.
Give us plasms, for without us
you could not
prove your charity.
- Oh great, Shakespeare
in the park.
- Give to a poor orphan
who is homeless, penniless,
crippled, and blind.
Give to the poor, the blind
and the deaf mute.
- How much have you
in your cup?
- Not a copper, not--
- Well if that's the
case, here's a copper.
- [Tom] Now shut up.
- Oh to do a good deed.
I suppose that one
copper isn't enough.
Where are you going?
- A werewolf!
Run for your lives.
- [Mike] Regain your sight
and grow your leg back.
- A werewolf!
- A werebear actually.
- [Tom] Like you're such a hunk.
- What kind of a good
deed will I have to do?
- What kind of bear am I?
- [Mike] Yogurt is
not a finger food.
- How sweet?
Naska, lets have the braid.
Quickly.
- Duty consultant,
Mrs. Khrushchev.
- Here.
- Mama.
Why not smear her eyebrows?
- Why is she putting
Bisquick on her face?
(laughing)
- [Mike] Why are you so mean
to me, Tanta Ernest Borgnine?
- Oh how lovely you look.
- Mama.
- [Tom] Don't let your
babies grow up to be cowboys.
- Naska's braid is
nicer than mine.
- Yours is worth more.
It was bought at the fair.
- I want you to cut off
her braid at the root.
- What could I drag
her by without a braid
on her head, I ask?
- Cut it off.
- Wait, I know.
I'll put a rag over
her braid to hide it.
- All right, then, hide it.
- Alfalfa's greatest role.
- [Mike] I should have
these caterpillars removed.
- Ah you (speaks Russian)
its much easier than working.
- Munchen guzzle?
What the hell?
(laughs)
- There you go.
See, now you're
dressed for housework
and now, my darling,
you put this on.
- [Tom] Its a Burger
King birthday crown.
- Like a princess, darling.
Exactly like a princess.
- Really?
- [Mike] I am pretty
hot, aren't I?
- A princess.
- A little red.
- And now a bag over the
head completes the look.
- I'm all tired out.
I'm sweating.
- Learn to suffer.
- [Mike] Like having Andrea
Dworkin make you over.
- No, not a princess.
- [Tom] She's got that
healthy clown glow.
- Oh no?
- You are a queen.
- [Mike] In that you look
like Freddie Mercury.
- She should just start
over from gene one.
- What kind of a
good deed can I do?
- [Tom] Maybe negotiate
lasting peace in the Mideast?
- [Mike] She's on her way back
from her stick distributor.
- [Tom] Not a very good canoe.
- I can't walk another step.
- Poor granny, here
let me help you.
- Yes, my boy, help me and
it will be a good deed.
- It will be a good deed?
- Help me.
- Boy, I'd be glad to help.
I need to do a good deed.
I need to very badly.
- and this is.
- Get on.
- Where do I get on?
- On my back.
- On your back?
- Climb on.
- Its light-bear transit.
- Do you live far
from here, granny?
- Oh yes, very very far.
- And?
- Its up the mountain,
and then down again,
and up the mountain
on the other side.
- That's all very good.
- Well if you think
so, that's fine.
But don't get all in a sweat.
- Here we go.
- Giddy up, let's go.
- [Tom] Babe!
(mock sobbing)
Oh, Babe.
- Knits all the time,
except in the morning
when she gulps down her
tea and lights the fire
and gets the breakfast.
Then she mops the floor,
and then when the
breakfast is ready she--
- I tell you, she's a marvel.
She's perfect in every respect
and no dream princess
could be lovelier.
- [Mike] And she's
available for sale or lease.
- This matchmaker
can certainly talk.
I think there was
something else we wanted.
- Yes.
- We hear you have
another daughter.
- Good lord, people say
the craziest things.
I am mama's only daughter.
The other ones not my sister.
- That's all right, we'll
have a look at the other one,
if you don't mind.
- Mama.
- Uh oh, there's a ripple in
the daughter market today.
- Well all right.
You'll see her since you insist.
Nastenka.
- [Tom] Quick, put
the dog in a dress.
- Naska.
Come here.
- [Mike] Well thanks
for listening.
Its just my fleas got me down.
- Get in there you little viper.
- Somebody needs viping.
- Nastenka, sweetheart
of mine, my honey child.
Come, let these
folks look at you.
- [Tom] Larry Drake
and Vanessa Redgrave.
- No, matchmaker, this
one won't do at all.
She looks like a scarecrow.
- [Mike] Now get out there and
do something Russo-Finnish.
- Our little idiot is
really horrible looking.
- Geeze.
- Her father.
- I uh--
(growls)
I won't.
I'll be quiet.
- Cabbage burp.
- All right, now start
the feast my dear guests.
- That's what I've
been waiting for.
I drink to your health.
- That's all very well but
my son likes goose giblets.
That's his favorite dish.
- Ah yes.
- [Mike] Oh Andy
goose giblets, oh.
- Naska.
- Oh no, your lovely daughter
should take care of it.
Its up to her.
That's the custom, you know?
- Mama.
- That way my son and
I can see what kind
of a bride we're getting.
- [Tom] Someday
I'll be a real boy.
(upbeat music)
- Well, Tom, I suppose we
ought to check in on those two
and make sure there's no--
- Little problem here, guys.
I'm a bear.
- Oh I'm so sure.
- Yeah, I'm a bear.
That little uh, you know, that
that mushroom head elf guy,
you know?
- yeah.
- He did it.
- Oh, huh.
And where did this happen?
- Just, you know, around.
Some luck, huh?
- You sure you just didn't
hot glue some fur to yourself?
- Hey, I wish.
- Yeah, well, huh a bear.
Well we better check
in on these two,
see how the peace
process is going.
- Bear (laughs).
What a feeb.
(growls)
(slobbery munching)
- Sorry.
- Well.
Thank you.
- You're welcome
and thank you for
laundering your cape.
- Oh well, think nothing of it.
- Would you like
some mashed banana?
- Oh no, no, no.
- You sure about that?
Its nice and rotten.
I don't eat it till the
fruit flies come a buzzing.
That's good eating.
- I'm sure that it is.
Yum.
(laughs)
- So, what are you up to?
- Oh I'm reading the
entire galactic library
of the Venusian
Eight system at once,
with my mind.
- Oh nice.
Are there pictures?
- Several trillion, yes.
- Oh.
Oh say, uh.
My toes feeling better.
Most of the seepage is dried up.
- Well, hallelujah.
- Do you...
Do you find that, uh,
well that the Lawgiver
can be mean sometimes?
- Well, its against
my culture to gossip.
- Oh sure, but do you?
- Yes, she can really be a
stone cold witch sometimes.
- Oh I know and she can
be so condescending.
- Oh preciously, its
like, oh I'm so great
and I don't have...
- Oh would you look at that?
It looks like that two finally
found something in common.
- Mike, help!
Crow ate half of me and
then buried me in the dirt.
- Mm, not bad.
- Crow, what is wrong with you?
- Well I told you,
Mike, I'm a bear.
- No, no haven't we talked
about this a hundred times
about you taking your bear
simulations to the extreme?
- Uh yeah.
- And what are you doing?
- Uh taking my bear
simulation to the extreme?
- There, now do you
see a connection?
- No.
- Oh.
Okay, well let me explain.
See, when you're a bear you
(alarm buzzing)
oh we got movie sign.
I'll explain later!
(doors clanking and whirring)
- Just gonna have to get
used to me as a bear.
- Oh shut up.
- Yeah right.
- [Old Woman] You're all
in a sweat, dear boy.
- Oh its really hot.
- Can you see some old
tumbled down houses yet?
- I see them.
- Well they're my castles, boy.
(Crow growls)
- [Mike] Yeah, stop it.
- Come on, hurry hurry,
or you'll catch cold.
Can't you feel it?
That cold mountain wind.
Come on, faster faster.
- [Mike] Forget the
good deed, eat her.
- Here we are,
we're home at last.
Yes at last we're home
and my home is my castle.
I'm much obliged to
you my handsome prince.
- [Tom] Most bears
don't carry compacts.
- Look, granny.
- True.
- Are you making fun of me?
- Of course not.
- [Ivan] Look at me before
you call me handsome.
- I like that.
- I can't very well
do that, my boy.
Its been at least,
yes its been 10 years
since I last looked
at something.
You see, I'm blind.
- [Ivan] Oh grandma, I wish I
could of gone blind for you.
- [Mike] Oh man.
- Oh no, how you talk.
- Father Mushroom lied.
- Who did?
- And I'll never
look at myself again.
- Oh blame the mirror.
- [Mike] Invasion of
the matryoshka people.
- What do you say, son?
- Let me talk.
He likes her very much.
Anybody can see she's
lovely, such beauty.
She's in perfect health.
I tell you all over.
- [Tom] She's
imprinting on the geese.
- Oh hurry.
(laughs)
- And the freelance
shame squad is there.
- [Tom] Oh the pond scum
is fleeing in terror
from her face.
- Marfusha, my darling daughter.
- Help!
Mama!
- [Mike] People's
distress is funny.
- [Tom] She caught
a water moccasin.
(shouts in Russian)
- My daughter, my daughter.
- Help, help.
- Well I guess you got
to be Russo-Finnish.
- Mama!
- Look my dear, maybe you
should have tied it tighter.
- Forget my daughter then.
Oh my sweet little dear.
- Why?
There's not telling what
bride a boy will take
and my son's not stupid.
He's ready to take a wife.
Aren't you?
- [Tom] Duh, I guh.
- That one.
(sobs)
- [Mike] The private
pain of Alfred E. Neuman.
(sobbing)
- He likes her.
- [Tom] One of the greatest
criminal masterminds
of the 20th century.
- She makes Olivia Hussy
look like Thelma Ritter.
- Nastenka's the one I want.
(laughs goofily)
(mock laughter)
- [Mike] We're gonna
starve this winter.
- [Tom] Well I suppose we
should get back to being ugly.
- [Mike] Let's go frighten
small children, shall we?
(growling)
- Chewbacca?
Where are you?
- [Tom] Hornets
don't make honey.
I found out the hard way.
- [Crow] Mommy, can
I go play at Timmy's?
- [Tom] Did I have to
eat all those campers?
- A stick, granny's stick.
How is she going to be
able to walk without it?
- I don't know, Richard Burton.
- I've got to take it to her.
- Very good, Ivan Lushka.
Very good.
- Oh man.
- [Mike] Scott Hamilton's
interpretation of
the Three Bears.
- [Tom] Mushroom guy's
staring to piss me off.
- Maybe I'm dreaming.
Maybe its just a vision.
Maybe that old magician
was only bragging.
Still, he cast a spell on me.
That's that feather
that brought me here.
- [Mike] Maybe I'm crazier
than an outhouse rat.
- And this is where I
first meet Nastenka.
- [Crow] Help me
Obi Wan Kenoboski.
- [Tom] Well got a great
stick out of the deal.
- There's that old stump
and the flowers
have really bloomed
and that wicked old
magicians laughing at me,
I suppose, I can't
shake off his spell.
- [Mike] Oh geeze, I
stepped in my own scat.
- [Tom] Uh, what?
Very confusing lesson.
- [Mike] So if you
speculate about doing good
its better than
actually doing it?
- Apparently.
- There's only one thing
I still have to do.
- Join the band Nelson.
- Farewell, Dash...
(tense music)
- [Mike] Salmon!
(tense classical music)
(Tom shouting rhythmically)
- Well that's taken care of,
now what are you gonna do
about the fact that
you're Finnish?
- Nastenka!
- [Mike] Hello?
- [Narrator] The
weeks have passed,
the winter winds
have begun to blow.
The old man takes his
daughter into the heart
of the forest.
Not that he wants
to do this at all,
it was the cantankerous
old woman's idea.
She insisted for so
long, nagged for so long,
that the cruel old man
finally yielded to her will.
- [Mike] Thanks, Dad.
- [Stepmother
Voiceover] I keep trying
to get Marfusha married
but everybody looks at
that little viper Nastika.
Take her far into the
forest and lose her.
I never want to see her again.
- [Tom] Do you have to
play that tape, Dad?
Its a little hard
on my self esteem.
- Still, traffic was light
and they made good time.
- [Mike] Oh I hope they
invent the wheel soon.
- [Tom] Just hear those
sleigh bells ring a ling,
jing jing jingling.
- No, my old woman
can go right ahead
and kill me if she wants.
- Fair.
- But I'm not going to do this.
Not to you, my daughter.
I won't leave you in the woods.
Oh, Zornaka, go.
Come on, boy, we're going back.
Go!
- [Mike] You sure this is
convenient for you, Dad?
- Oh Zornaka, I don't care
if she waves the poker at me,
or the pitchfork.
Let her rave, I'm
not afraid anymore.
No my darling daughter,
I'm not afraid anymore!
I'll tell her what
I think, you'll see.
Ho, Zornaka. Ho.
- He has the spine
of a tube worm.
- [Nastenka
Voiceover] She's going
to make my poor
daddy so miserable.
She'll drive him mad.
Goodbye, daddy.
- [Mike] Still, it
was good for him
to get out of the
basement for awhile.
- [Nastenka Voiceover] Remember
your daughter who loved you.
- [Tom] Val Kilmer
as Prince Valiant.
- Nastia!
- [Mike] I need a haircut!
(laughs)
- Wolves are just
laughing out loud.
They got the B squad
in to eat this guy.
- [Tom] Fresh is
better, get Mentos fresh
and full of life.
- [Mike] What would you
do for a Klondike Bar?
(tense classical music)
- Oh, damn potholes.
- Nastia!
(mimics engine revving)
- You over there at the house,
come on, get moving.
Open the doors wide.
- [Crow] That horse
is not a real blonde.
- Oh, Zornaka.
- Mama.
- What's the matter with you?
- That's enough.
I'm not putting up
with this anymore.
Now its my...
- [Mike] Turn to get
down in the basement.
- I won't say it, I'll be quiet.
(laughing)
- Marfusha, go on
into the house.
You will catch a cold, darling.
(laughs)
(Crow growls)
you better watch out.
- Well I showed her.
Read her the riot
act, all right.
Yup.
- Nastenka's gone.
- [Tom] I got more you
and I've been neutered.
- [Mike] Don't touch
me, you coward.
- [Tom] Someone's
pickling something.
- Hey, not a bear anymore.
Mushroom guy turned me back.
- [Mike] Really?
You didn't just peel it off?
- No.
(tense music)
- [Mike] Wow.
- Oh little cabin, turn
your back to the forest
and turn your face to me.
- [Mike] Big Bird got developed.
(squawking)
This guys actually Jamaican.
- [Tom] Al Lewis, survivalist.
(yawns)
- [Baba Yaga] What do you want?
- She's 800 years young.
- Ah, Ivan.
Why did you come here?
You were not invited.
Now you turn my house around
and awaken me out
of a sound sleep.
The house had its back to you.
Whatever made you
turn it around?
- Oh don't be angry, hunchback
fairy, don't be angry.
(laughing)
Help me to find Nastenka.
I must save her.
Please, she needs help badly.
- Don't expect any
help from me, Ivan.
I won't give you
the slightest help.
- [Tom] Oh chuckles
is over here.
- Now my little house.
(bell rings)
About face.
Turn your back to Ivan
and face the woods again.
- [Mike] Oh its
Bill Gate's house.
Its voice controlled.
- Turn your back to
the woods and face me.
- Face the woods, turn
your back to Ivan.
- House, face me with
your back to the woods.
- Face the woods, turn
your back to Ivan.
- Come to Knott's Berryfarm
and ride the unstable house.
- You hooligan.
- I don't care how hard you try.
I'm going to have
the upper hand.
Face me!
- Face the woods.
- [Mike] Oh no.
No, no leg kicks please.
- Face me.
- Face the woods.
- Face the woods
- Face me.
- Face the woods.
- Face the uh...
- [Tom] All right,
come up for a beer.
- All right.
You'll see, won't always
have the upper hand.
Your strength is only
earthly strength.
In the end it won't help.
Like ours use witch kind.
(creaking)
- Please.
- Don't.
- [Mike] Don't do that.
- Don't give up yet,
my young knight.
- [Mike] His performance
is so wooden.
- Quick, give him
Dutch Elm disease.
- [Tom] This is an
Earth First fantasy.
- [Mike] Take that,
logging industry.
- I've heard that tree gang
violence is increasing.
(laughs)
- [Mike] Don't you.
- [Tom] Oh they got
him in a hodi ring.
- [Mike] Miracle-Gro
worked too well.
- [Trees] One, two.
Three!
- [Tom] In you pixies
go, through the door,
through the window.
- Oh self delivering lumber.
- [Mike] I just hate it
when the trees just come in.
- [Tom] If I had a tree,
I'd keep it in the yard.
- This way, right this way.
You make a find roast, all nice.
- [Crow] Uh oh,
roasted nuts, oh boy.
- Ivan, you can't win.
Struggle Ivan, come on
fight back all you like.
Nothings going to stop me.
You're my supper.
- Look, hunchback
fairy, I'm sorry.
- Are you afraid?
- Well I've never
been pushed in an oven
and its the first
I've sat on a shovel.
- [Mike] The flat part anyway.
(cackles)
- Please show me how
to sit on a shovel.
I don't know.
- [Tom] Hello, Mrs. Non Gorilla.
- Take the handle.
- All right.
- What's the world coming to?
The youth of today
wasn't taught anything.
You see, you don't have to be
a wizard to do that, stupid.
- I hope its warm
enough for you.
(shouts)
- [Baba Yaga] I'm cooking!
I'm roasting.
(shouting)
- All right, get out of here.
I'll turn you all into kindling.
Go on, get out.
Now run for your lives.
(Mike humming Benny Hill theme)
- [Tom] Split up,
its our only hope.
- [Crow] Oh I forgot
to preheat the oven.
- Its hot in here!
I'm sizzling.
- [Mike] Is this weird
or is it just me?
- A steam bath
never hurt anybody.
And now tell me, where is she?
Tell me where I
can find Nastenka.
- Geeze.
- Tell me how I
can save Nastenka.
- Oh save her, save her.
- All right, you old
witch, in you go again.
- No.
- [Mike] Robert
Mapplethorpe's Strega Nona.
- You cook a little longer.
- No, Ivan, no.
- [Tom] What.
I mean when, whom.
I'm sorry, who.
- Later, in twinkly
winkly pixie wixie land.
(singing in Russian)
(whimsical music)
- [Mike] Hey Jack
Frost, finally.
- Wanna translate, Tom?
- [Tom] Its colder than
a bucket of penguin poop.
Its colder than a
polar bear's butt.
The dogs are sticking
to the fire hydrants.
- Bye bye.
- [Tom] That means bye bye.
- Thank you.
- [Mike] What do
you want, Frost?
(speaking Russian)
- Hey, he can make
the film reverse.
(speaking Russian)
- [Mike] We will bury you.
- I do frost and I do it well.
- [Tom] At least its not
a film about Jack Abcess.
- [Mike] Eat lead, Spring.
- [Tom] Frosty lucky trees,
they're magically delicious.
- So he bought a flocking gun?
Big deal.
- [Mike] Jack Frost opened fire
on a stand of willows today.
- [Tom] I don't really need, um,
its gonna ruin my buds.
Oh I'm dead.
- [Mike] You know,
I'm from Wisconsin.
I've seen plenty of this.
Can we move on?
- Smilla's sense of crap.
- [Tom] Although the director
left this somewhat ambiguous
I'm getting the idea
that he's frosting trees.
- Could be.
Don't frost her, you big.
- [Mike] I pray for the
death of Jack Frost.
- [Tom] You work for
summer, don't ya, don't ya!
- Where did this little
marvel come from?
Little girl, where
were you until now?
- Back off, Frost.
- I, at home.
- At home.
Tell me, don't you feel cold?
- Oh I feel warm enough,
grandfather Frost.
- [Frost] You're warm?
- I'm warm.
- [Mike] Look, I've got mace.
- [Tom] My muffins!
(coughing)
- Oh god, my heart.
- Even now are you warm?
Graceful creature.
- I'm warm, Grandfather Frost.
I am warm, grandfather.
- [Mike] Am I gonna
have to call the cops?
- You're a very good girl.
Not the contradicting kind.
- [Tom] Yes I am.
- Here you are, my little
marvel, here's my cloak.
- It smells like dried Ensure.
- How bout you then?
You'll be cold.
- Me, cold?
(laughing)
- Why, I'm made
of fleshy Thinsulate.
(laughing)
- A bird.
- Lets eat it.
- [Mike] Wow, bottom line,
don't mess with Jack Frost.
- Don't bother, my sweet,
it won't do any good.
- [Mike] Its dead, dead.
- In my magic scepter lies the
power that spreads the frost.
- You have no pity.
You're cruel.
- Oh I am not at
all without pity.
I am not cruel.
I do pity this poor
little frozen bird.
But any living creature who
touches my magic scepter
will never wake up again.
- Admittedly its
a design flaw but.
- What's the matter, my sweet?
- Goodbye, Grandfather Frost.
- [Frost] What's
wrong, pretty one?
- I'm freezing.
- Who, who who!
I say.
Quickly, quickly, my ice sleigh.
- [Tom] Whoa.
- Like the wind.
- [Tom] I think you
got an engine fire.
(Jack Frost mimic
engine revving)
- He's making that sound.
- [Mike] The new
1976 Chevy Sleigh.
- Don't lose heart, don't
lost hope, my sweet.
You won't freeze.
- No, I'll take the bus, thanks.
- That's it.
That's it.
Don't worry.
You see, they'll be
dancing at your wedding.
(laughing)
onward!
- [Tom] I just got to
get some jumper cables
and recharge my scepter!
(laughs)
- [Mike] Wait till I open
her up on the freeway.
- Do you have any
good tapes, Jack?
(whimsical music)
- [Tom] Hey I'm
stuck in a snow bank.
Hello!
- [Mike] Yup, magic sleigh.
- [Jack] Feeling
warmer, my sweet?
- Could we put the
top up, though?
- [Tom] He stole my purse!
(upbeat music)
- Nastenka in love.
It doesn't mean a thing.
- [Tom] This is what
happens when you don't cook
your witch thoroughly.
- Yes, its nothing but a joke.
Here take this, a
sheep skin cloak.
- Don't mind the dandruff.
(sneezes)
- Poor boy.
You must mind your
health, young man.
You might catch cold.
- [Mike] Its nice to
see they've gotten past
the oven incident.
- Listen now I am--
(Shushes)
- [Crow] Dr. Quinn's on.
- Foulest hell.
Where is (mumbles).
- [Tom] Oink, ma'am.
- What's that?
- Oh at last a ride in the snow.
Its faster than the
winds that blow.
It skims by itself
over the snow.
Over the snow, it skims
by itself toward the place
where Nastenka now lies.
- [Tom] She left it in drive.
- Look out for my
sheepskin coat.
Its almost new.
Don't forget to give
it to back to me.
- (laughs) give it back
to me, that's great.
(laughing)
- [Mike] Well.
Sooie, uh pig, sooie.
- [Tom] I wouldn't trade
being a witch for anything.
- Well better get ready,
the trees are coming over
for the game later.
- [Mike] Wow, Miami Steve
Van Zandt did not age well.
- How weary I am,
so weary, so very.
- [Tom] Shake that money maker.
- My aching bones
are very weary.
My aching bones are very weary.
I aint gone over.
- Well back to the day care.
- [Mike] Okay pull your
sleigh over, Frost.
Let's see your license.
(upbeat music)
- Can't drive 55.
- [Tom] Wait till he finds
out I blew up the bridge.
(shouts)
- [Mike] Let's just swing into
this IHOP for a short stack.
- Yes, every cultures mythology
features the young hero
chasing a pig sleigh.
- [Tom] Here at Skidoo
testing grounds.
- Oh I feel so ill,
so ill, so ill.
I haven't got a fever.
- She's a maniac, maniac.
(Tom whooping like
Three Stooges)
- [Mike] Just calm down
and give me my Fancy Feast.
- Oh oh I can't sleep or eat.
I feel low.
I can't rest, I feel low.
(bell clanging)
(shouting)
He dare to insult the
old hunchback fairy.
- [Tom] Look, shut up!
Get it together,
what is your problem?
- Here I wanted to
eat that young idiot
and instead of that
I almost let myself
getting eaten up.
Silly witch that I was.
- [Mike] No, no
you're a good witch.
You have to believe that.
- How do you like my website?
- Oh hello, kitty.
- [Mike] Really really don't.
(Crow growls)
- Oh wait, sorry.
- The velvet paw.
Little kitty with
the jet black coat.
- [Tom] Actually
I'm dutch mahogany.
- With the silken fur.
You've got to help
me, little kitty.
Run skip and fly over the snow.
Go find Ivan's darling
and cause her death.
Go.
- [Mike] Yeah right.
I'm gonna go lick myself.
(shrill whistling)
- Yeah that's what I'd
like to do with this movie,
just scamper away from it.
- And now we shall
now wait and see.
(laughing)
- [Tom] How are ya?
- When am I gonna
pass this witch?
- [Tom] Finnish house par-tay.
- [Mike] Oh good.
Eat my slush.
- Well Mike, I guess this
is just a magical land.
I hate magical lands.
- [Tom] Me, too.
We now switch you
live to pig cam.
- [Mike] I'm bacon!
Bacon bacon bacon.
Mm bacon, I'm bacon.
- Okay, just idle
down around this tree.
- [Tom] This just isn't right.
I'm a cat.
I should be laying out
hairy pukes on a new carpet
and ignoring my owners.
Not this.
(tense classical music)
- Hey, Puff how'd your
spaying go yesterday?
- [Tom] Wait a minute, okay.
- [Mike] Oh its Queen
Frostine's house.
- [Tom] Let's try this.
Ow I slipped on your
steps, I'm gonna sue, ow.
- Don't you worry
now, little girl.
Everything will
be all right, see.
He's never going to forget you.
Well.
- Stoli?
- I'm going out now
to take a look around
and see how the birch
trees and pines are doing.
I must see to it
that all is in order.
- [Tom] Or they dock my pay.
- And you'll be the
mistress of the house.
- [Mike] So I guess instead
of vacuuming this floor
you Zamboni it.
- You take care of the house.
I'll come back very soon.
- That guy spends a lot of time
cutting out paper
snowflakes, huh?
- [Tom] Is this true love
or just a kidnapping?
(whimsical music)
- [Mike] Bob Keeshan
is mister natural.
- Ah ha, my plan
worked perfectly.
(hums tense music)
(meows)
- [Mike] You ordered
a hairball, ma'am?
- She's in trouble, I feel it.
- Get down in that
basement, old man.
(growls)
- Where do you
think you're going?
Come back, go right
back into the house.
- [Tom] They're so in need
of a family therapist.
- [Mike] I'm not a chew toy.
I'm the old man of the house.
- Tramps on the loose
and he's got a gun.
- [Tom] I've never
been in such heat.
(energetic classical music)
- [Mike] He's chasing
an Italian minstrel.
- The Incredible Journey
the one man show.
- [Tom] I need to go out.
Oh wait.
- Tiapa.
- [Mike] Please, I don't
want human hair on my fur,
I'm allergic.
- Nice, kitty.
- Put my food on a crystal plate
or I'll whizz on your socks.
- Where are you going, kitty?
- [Tom] Litter box.
- [Mike] All right, score,
I thought it was going
to take weeks to do that.
- [Frost Voiceover]
Whoever touches my scepter
will never wake up again.
- Yeah well maybe it should be
stored a little more safely.
- [Tom] At least a
Mr. Yuck sticker.
- [Mike] Oh where
the hell did I park?
- That winter snows.
- So the premise of this movie
is that everyone is just
nuttier than all get out?
- Stands there feeling proud.
- [Tom] Deutschland
Deutschland (sings in German).
- Stands the forbidding froud.
The gales of winter
blow and sing.
- And rip the skin
off your face.
- Oh oh this will not do.
It simply will not do.
Quickly, quickly, we must
sprinkle you with frost.
- [Tom] But will it do?
- Oh you're such an
idiot, you dunce,
you nitwit, you donkey.
You left your
specter in the house.
Without you can't
freeze a thing.
- [Mike] I enjoy watching
people's mental illness.
- You moron, your a
worthless piece of crap,
like something I
scrap off my shoe.
(babbles)
Duh hoy.
Here comes Jack Frost, an idiot.
- [Tom] Clear out the bathroom!
- Hello there.
Who lives in this house?
- okay, stay cool.
(knocking at door)
- [Frost] Who will
open the door?
- So he lives in a sort of
Christian Pagan fun house?
- Nastenka, come back already.
- [Tom] Oh great,
the toilet backed up.
(tense music)
(doors clanking and whirring)
- Well sorry, Professor Smirnoff
was such a disappointment
before, guys.
But you'll be happy to hear
I've hired a more solid expert
on Russia at great
personal expense.
Well expense to you, Mike.
I maxed out your credit cards.
- What, Crow you can't--
- And I'll also need your
assistance with this easel.
- Fine.
- Come on, Mike.
Humor him.
- Let's just do it.
- Now, what film delved deeper
into the former soviet union's
relationship with the US
than Sylvester
Stallone's Rocky IV
wherein he fights
a Russian superman?
- Well I can think
of a lot of films--
- And what better embodies
the spirit of Rocky IV
than the rousing rock
anthem Eye of the Tiger
from Rocky III?
- Huh?
- And who knows that song
better than a key member
of the band Survivor,
which recorded it.
I'm talking of course about...
- Their lead singer
and songwriter--
- Their drummer.
Who technically
didn't join the group
till seven years
after Eye of the Tiger
but who better to speak
for this drummer than?
- His wife.
- His manager.
- His great aunt
Gladys Fletcher.
- Of course.
- Who sadly passed
away three years ago.
But her old friend
Eunice Torgeson.
- Is here and we're
gonna talk to her now--
- And I have been playing
phone tag all day.
So in her place, I've
contacted her estranged
half brother, Earl Torgeson,
a butcher in Stanford, Maine
who specializes in handmade
old world sausages.
- Sausages.
- and Russia, of course.
- Of course.
- We now go live
to Mr. Torgeson.
Ah, professor Torgeson, where
does our movie Jack Frost
fit in vis a vis the
mytho-poetic dimensions
of later Russian literature.
Ah, Mr. Torgeson, slightly
bad connection, sir,
you may have to speak
up a bit louder.
- Hello, Toregson's Meats.
- Ah I see, interesting,
interesting.
And do you see
themes in this film
or indeed any other
traditional Russian folklore
which prepare us for the
tumultuous Russian politics
of modern times?
- Got it, Mrs. Kreongin.
Two pounds of bratwurst,
one chedderwrust,
three of blood sausage.
- Fascinating.
- Great.
- Great, well.
- Okay, then.
- Well thank you for your time.
Thank you.
Oh boy, food for thought, huh?
Wow, Russia.
Its definitely worth
all that money.
Well Mike's money.
- Get him!
(shouting)
Son of a.
- We'll be right back.
(upbeat music)
(tense classical music)
Apparently there's no
Finnish word for subtle.
- Ah.
- [Mike] Come to mama.
- Love is a battlefield.
- Ah.
(meowing)
Very good.
You're going to get your reward.
The best reward there is.
- [Crow] A half rotted anchovy.
- Oh you're a good kitty.
Yes, something nice, kitty.
A bowl of cream for kitty.
- [Tom] But I'm
lactose intolerant.
- You've earned it.
My little black imp.
(screeching meows)
- [Crow] Which one of
them is doing that?
- [Mike] I don't know.
- All is fair.
- [Mike] Don't do that.
- Fair is foul.
- [Tom] Ah hello.
- And here is something
for you, too, here.
Deviled ham just for you.
You've earned it.
You little pink devil.
- [Mike] Deviled ham?
That's sick, I can't believe
you're making me eat this.
- [Tom] The new Ace
of Base record is out!
(whimsical music)
(dog barking)
- [Mike] Bad dog.
Stop it, don't do
that to my leg.
Stop it.
- Give me the damn
Snausage, man,
I know its in your pocket.
- [Tom] I don't want
to go to church, Fido,
I'm agnostic.
- [Mike] Its the
Crystal Cathedral North.
- [Frost] Greetings, Ivan.
- Killed your girlfriend.
Coffee?
- The widow's son.
- Greetings, Grandfather Frost.
- Have you come for Nastenka.
- For Nas...
- [Tom] Or are you here
about the 87 Buick?
- [Mike] Let me take
you around back.
Show you the new lawn, boy.
- So a couple more
snowmobilers ate it last night.
(dog whining)
- [Tom] No ones fed
me in about four days.
- [Mike] Oh its a
Fantasuites room.
- Look she was already
frozen when I got here.
It aint my fault, man.
- Nastenka.
- [Tom] Its a positive ID then.
- She's asleep.
- [Mike] Oh am I
that transparent?
- So Frost, you killed her,
that's the long and short of it.
- Why is she
sleeping now by day?
- [Frost] Ivan Lushka,
she sleeps day and night.
- [Tom] She's really lazy.
- [Mike] I'm out of wiper fluid.
- I hurt your
feelings, Nastenka.
Won't you please forgive me?
- And my Ah-Ha hairdo?
- Please.
- Take on me.
- [Tom] Take me on.
(bell rings)
- She's done.
- [Mike] So she sleeps forever
only in a relative sense?
- Yes.
- [Tom] Geeze, its the first
time I've relaxed in weeks.
Leave me alone.
- [Mike] Oh its you.
- [Tom] I'll be gone, so take...
- Ivan Lushka.
- Well now I can
call the Debbie girl.
Oh, oh hi honey.
- Nastenka.
(whimsical music)
- [Mike] What the hell?
Its supposed to keep
her sleeping forever.
Now where's that bird
just running around free
outside somewhere?
- It took years of
intense training
to get the dog to
walk like that.
- Ivan Lushka.
- [Tom] You want to
start the Cardigans?
- How nice you are now.
- Am I really?
- I like you better.
- My darling little Nastenka.
You're right, you know,
I used to be selfish,
now I do good deeds
from morning till night.
Yeah, see what a
good man I've become.
- There's something
on your cheek.
- Is there?
- Its fur, a spot of brown
hair like bear fur, I think.
- Oh no, that's just a big zit.
- I was only
joking, Ivan Lushka.
- [Ivan] Nastenka.
- [Tom] Yeah well you're
still frozen okay.
- [Mike] My famous
Yankee bean soup.
- They're swimming in my
chili, the little creeps.
- [Baba Yaga] Disappear image.
- [Tom] Oh evil sith
bath, soothe me.
- [Mike] So weary.
So weary.
- Get out of my sight, traitors!
Parasites!
Get out.
- Ma'am?
- What can we do, old owl?
- [Tom] What, what?
- Let's try it,
we might succeed.
- [Tom] Kena Navacholola's
childhood was not a happy one.
- [Mike] She's become
one of those heroin chic
magazine models.
- Its good to see Anthony
Michael Hall working again.
(metal rattles)
- [Tom] Rutton
Balsima's Trotsky.
- The other old women have
stupid old men at home, too
but you're the limit.
- Yes, dear.
- Why did you have
to drag your daughter
into the forest?
To amuse grandfather Frost?
To feed packs of hungry wolves?
- I love you, dear.
- You, you, you.
- I won't say it, I'll be quiet.
- I can't help it,
I miss Nastika.
I remember I used to tug
that big braid of hers.
What a grand feeling.
But I can't pull a thing anymore
now that Nastia's gone.
You're almost bald and
if I pulled your beard
it would come right off you.
(giggling)
- [Mike] This Fin's life .
- Shut your Kringle hole.
- [Mike] Classic case of
Munchausen by Proxy syndrome.
- Look, its all your fault.
I hit my darling daughter
on her rosy cheek.
I'd never did that if
Naskia had been here.
- [Man] Looks who here.
- [Tom] Thank you,
anonymous voice.
(sleigh bells rattling)
- Just hear those
sleigh bells ring a ling
ring ching a ling ring.
- [Mike] Parson Brown
the Russian tour.
- [Tom] Its the three
horses of the apocalypse.
- [Mike] The fourth dropped out
cause he had too many
afterschool activities.
- Its Santa Claus Junior.
- [Mike] Hi, behold
a pale horse.
- [Tom] Mom looks like
Carol O'Connor in Drag.
- Ah the yuppies are back.
- [Mike] I guess they got one
of them quickie
Icelandic marriages.
- [Tom] Mom, I
married a Beefeater.
- [Mike] And the vicious cycle
of a dish to pass continues.
- We spit on your doorstep.
(spits)
- [Mike] Please take me
with you, please, please.
- I'd like you to meet.
- [Tom] Uh, what's
your name again?
- Ivan Lushka, my fiance.
- I can't look at them,
honey, they're horrible.
- Father, listen to me, I
will explain everything.
Grandfather Frost
found me in the forest.
First he took me with
him to his dwelling.
- [Mike] Then he
kind of killed me.
- He arranged the
betrothal with Ivan Lushka.
Then he gave me this dowery.
- Gummy bears.
- [Woman] Isn't the
bridegroom handsome?
- [Woman] And Nastenka
looks just like a princess.
- [Woman] No like a queen.
- And Marfusha looks like
a brick sack of potatoes,
rotten potatoes.
(laughing)
- All right, get out of here.
Get out of here.
- [Tom] Oh a hockey
game breaks out.
- All of you get out of here.
- [Mike] We'll stay at a hotel.
- [Marfusha] I'll show you
who's a sack of potatoes.
- Marfusha, now, please
don't get excited.
- Get out of here, all of you.
I want a fiance, I
want precious stones.
I want stones, stones.
(shouting)
- [Narrator] So according
to Marfusha's wishes
and the old woman's order,
the old men took Marfusha
into the heart of the forest
and left her beneath
a tall pine tree.
- [Mike] Where she drank
herself into oblivion, the end.
- [Tom] What's on the spit?
You cook a mighty
fine rabbit, pilgrim.
- [Mike] Its a weird place
for a tailgate party.
- Its Mrs. Creosote.
- [Tom] Oh I love
Coco Lopez neat.
- [Mike] And the month's
rations are gone in an hour.
- Tip O'Neil after
the retirement.
- [Mike] Vedalias.
- [Tom] Mm, peat moss, yum.
- Tell me, are you
warm, little one?
- [Mike] Dun dun dun.
- Ha, warm.
Warm he says.
Can't you see my hands
and feet are frozen?
- [Tom] But its
nearly 10 degrees out.
Its sweltering.
- Who is this freak of nature?
- [Mike] My pop overs.
(upbeat music)
- Once more, let me ask,
are you warm, little girl?
- All right, pal.
You're dead, man.
- [Mike] You just got
yourself a big sled load
of whoop ass, Frost.
- Bring on my fiance
and my dowery, too.
A real big dowery
and make it quick.
- You stuttering frosted freak.
(panting)
- Hey.
- You understand?
- [Tom] Its its its.
- Its a convention of
Michael Palin imitators.
- Levon Helm.
- [Mike] Yeah tell me about it.
(singing in Russian)
- [Tom] They're singing about
controlling their nose hair.
(sings in Russian)
- [Mike] Sadly, this was
Chet Baker's last role.
- Its the seven dwarves.
Filthy, Rotting, Lousy,
Skanky, Scabby, Septic
and Doc.
- [Tom] You know its so
true what they say though.
- [Mike] Original soundtrack
on Polygram records.
- Silence, to your stations.
- We have stations?
- We're going to rob.
- [Tom] And we're gonna rock.
- Here they come.
(tense classical music)
- [Mike] Wow those winged
monkeys now use jet packs.
- [Tom] Cool.
(Tom barks)
- [Mike] Too much air
traffic, I got to go around.
- Ah ha.
Grandmother has come to see us.
- And she is hot.
- Hello, hello.
- Pah, here she is.
She hasn't bit the dust.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Come on
guys, I got feelings.
- Woodland giants, little
bandits, darling bandits,
would you please help me?
I'll reward you all.
- With what?
- With two tubs of gold nuggets
and six pairs of
sterling silver ingots
and all the copper I've got.
Any amount
and all for easy work.
- Give this to us!
- [Mike] And foot
massages for everyone.
- Oh my god, these
are her teeth.
- That should hold them,
coppers good enough for them.
You will get gold.
Oh not so fast,
do the work first.
- Don't you trust us?
- Oh don't you trust
me to trust you?
- [Tom] Watch me break dance.
- Quiet now, listen, listen.
(upbeat music)
- [Mike] Here's the king,
here comes the big number one.
The king is taking too long.
- Say, Herb, have
you eve noticed
how none of us
ever win this race?
- [Tom] You know, Phil,
I don't even mind that
but I'd just like to see a horse
of another color just once.
- [Mike] Every time I tell
myself I'm not gonna turn left
when he pulls that rope and
then I just go and do it again.
- Wow fast, I hope he remembers
to pump the brakes in the snow.
- [Tom] So honey
do we have a house
or are we just gonna
drive around all the time?
- [Mike] Big trees,
the new IMAX movie.
- No, no really its true.
I heard it right
from my own mouth.
- [Tom] I got lost about
30 miles back, honey.
Hey, hey hey hey.
- [Mike] Honey you're
going too fast,
honey there's a mogul,
watch it, honey.
Honey.
(goofy laugh)
- Watch, I'm gonna
hit this raccoon.
- [Tom] Metaphorically,
I think the suggestion
that marriage is a dizzying
mad, existential ride
to nowhere.
- [Mike] Or that
niceness is fun.
- [Crow] Yeah its termites.
- There, all right.
You scoundrels, listen to
what I'm asking you to do.
Its very simple.
- [Mike] Get, get away.
- Soon a boy and a girl
are going to come by.
Ivan, the widow's son,
and Ivan's fiancee.
You must capture
them, tie them up,
and then torture them.
Understand?
- We understand.
- Man your stations.
- [Mike] Cirque De Solei.
- Don't look up my dress.
- [Tom] Aren't these
ambushes phony?
- [Mike] False alarm,
its only Bjork.
- Where dwarves dare.
(whistles)
- [Tom] Surprise,
happy birthday.
- [Mike] A wild cat
strike brought out
in the Keebler
cookie mines today.
- Take that, Hamburglar.
- Hurry, its Nastenka.
- [Tom] Russia's first
ever pantsing begins.
- Hold him.
- [Mike] Piling on,
15 yard penalty.
- That's how we do a job.
- Ivan Lushka!
(laughs)
- Very good.
- All right, granny,
where's the gold?
- Yes, right away.
I have it here.
- Under this spare goiter.
- [Tom] That means he likes her.
- An old lady, you
dirty (shouts).
- [Mike] The flying batch.
- Surrender Ivan, or
Nastenka will learn
to sit on a shovel.
- That's her answer
to everything.
- Come on, men.
- [Mike] Get Sven Nyquist.
- Its, oh nevermind.
- [Tom] Cymbal fist,
the new action hero.
- [Mike] I just
know someones gonna
end up in the wood chipper.
- You coward!
- She's a sweet girl
but you got to admit
she's also kind of a jinx.
- Here I come, charge!
- [Mike] Don't you
think if you were magic
you'd order up some
better clothes?
- My broom.
I'm a witch and I
can't move without it.
- Well you should
of diversified more.
- [Tom] I never liked you.
I'm gonna make this tighter.
(growling)
- [Mike] I thought I was Dale.
- Jackie Chan is Ivan Lushka.
- [Tom] Ma'am, could you
wiggle just a little bit?
- On your feet, hurry.
- [Mike] Oh yeah, its
raining cinematic payoff.
- These are own
clubs coming down.
- Isn't it ironic,
don't you think?
(groaning)
- [Tom] The audience
is listening.
(grunting)
- [Mike] Meanwhile,
at the baptismal font.
- Well this isn't funny, no I
think that guys really hurt.
Mike, see?
- [Mike] Just take my
sample case and scram.
- Ivan Lushka.
- [Tom] Wait up-shka.
- Nastenka.
- Ivan, look out.
- Oh you old witch.
- Hold it, I'm a poor
grandmother of a hunchback.
- We won't have the
slightest pity for you.
- [Mike] I'm quite miffed
at your attempted murder.
(barking)
- And the dog ate her, the end.
Okay.
- [Mike] Oh she's
really a great old gal.
- Ivan Lushka.
- Its over between us.
- Nastenka.
- [Tom] Let's go to America
and start the
Brighton Beach mob.
- She got a trunk of
jewels, a box of them,
but you'll see Marfusha
will get two of each.
Two francs fill of them
and two jewel cases filled
with precious stones.
- [Mike] Oh yes,
dear, I love you.
- What do you mean by (grunts)?
She'll get four trusts and
she'll get four jewel cases.
- [Tom] Just waiting
for my death, honey.
Sooner the better.
- [Mike] Look the Johnson's
have a new snow blower.
- The man he found
Nastenka is a peasant
but Marfusha is sure
to get a prince.
You wait still she comes back.
- Dear, I'm just gonna
nip and kill myself, dear.
- Here they are.
- [Tom] My babushka.
Oh I've got it on.
(tense classical music)
- [Mike] Its Prokofiev
and this time he's pissed.
- Deck the halls
in bows of holly.
(humming)
- [Tom] Live in a Swiss colony.
- [Mike] You know
they fight a lot
but they stay together
because the sex is fantastic.
- Its a three pig open sled.
- [Tom] Oh Wilbur,
on Gordy, on Babe.
- [Mike] Why, they're
proud stately animals.
- The royal Lipizzaner pigs.
- [Tom] This is a
full family Christmas.
- [Mike] Yes dear,
my fault, don't hit.
- Yes hello, awfully
nice to see you.
- [Tom] Watch it, you.
- Where's your dowery?
- Here.
- You idiot.
(shouting)
- [Mike] Counting us.
- And poop, gentlemen.
(sobs)
(crowd laughing)
- [Tom] A young Mike Nelson.
- [Mike] Hey.
- Proving again that slightly
unattractive people are evil.
- [Tom] Your pain gives us joy.
- Duh.
- I won't say it, I'll be quiet.
- Now I'll give the orders.
- [Mike] Because the crows have
taught me a valuable lesson.
- Let the wedding begin.
- And they became professional
Faberge egg imitators.
- [Tom] Man the
Bulgarian woman's chorus
is a rocking reception band.
(chanting Russian singing)
- [Mike] They were
flanked at the reception
by Pappy Yoakem
and Mother Theresa.
- Mother took me down
seconds after I took power.
- [Tom] Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club wedding.
- [Mike] Please enjoy
the deep fried rocks.
- You know, you just know
they're going to be dancing
to Proud Mary in about an hour.
- [Tom] Enjoy a mug of
penetrating wood finish.
- [Both] Hey.
Hey.
Hey
hey hey hey.
- Yeah right, until a
mushroom guy moved in.
(doors clanking and whirring)
(laughing)
Oh hey, Servo, new dress?
- No Mike, I'm really cute.
In fact, I'm darling.
- You're dowling?
What wooden rods?
- I don't know what
he's trying to say.
- No, no I'm darling.
- Dowling.
Dowling, he's Joe Dowling.
Artistic director of
the Guthrie Theater.
- He doesn't wear a dress.
- I don't mean to criticize--
- Oh no no you stupid.
Its very simple.
I'm adorable.
- You're endowable.
Oh I see, Mike.
I think what he's trying
to say is that if you and I
wanted to set up an endowment
he's the guy to talk to.
- No you stupid
loathsome freaks.
I'm precious, I'm as
cute as a little button.
- Oh the widow Buddig,
you know Carl Buddig
pressed meat products?
- Oh excellent corn beef.
- He's the widow.
- You make me sick.
Look just forget it,
you couple of morons.
I'm cute, okay, I'm cute
like that scrawny little
square head in the movie
but just forget it.
The whole cute things
in the crapper.
- I'm sorry, Tom.
- Oh can it, will you?
Man I need a belt and a smoke.
I'm starting to
sweat right through
the damn babushka.
- That's unpleasant.
Oh BJ and the Bear are calling.
- Uh huh.
- But you know what's a
really great ape movie?
- What's a really
great ape movie?
- Every Which Way but Loose.
Now that's a really
great ape movie.
- Yeah, damn that's
a good movie.
You know what's an
even better ape movie?
- What's that?
- Any Which Way You Can.
- Oh get out.
Get out.
- You get out, its
a better ape movie.
- Ah then we'll see.
We'll get Mike down here.
Hey say, Mike, we need
you down here again.
Oh there you are.
- Good, good okay.
Wait a second, wait
a second, okay.
- Okay well get the man
a long neck will you?
- Got to give me a long neck.
Here we go.
- Give him a tallski.
- Okay, Mike, now which
is the better ape movie?
Every Which Way but Loose
or Any Which Way You Can?
- Every Which Way
but Loose or any,
you know I have to say I
think Any Which Way You Can
is a funnier movie.
(laughing)
But on the other hand, you know,
Every Which Way but
Loose is better made.
- Oh I don't believe it.
- In your face.
- What the hell?
Do you mean Every Which Way but
Loose is the best ape movie?
What do you know
about ape movies?
Snag me a brew, will you?
- Get the woman a beer.
- The best ape movie,
the best ape movie ever
is Dunston Checks In.
- Ah.
- End of story.
Until next time, Nelson.
Fresh pain awaits.
- Oh excuse me, I'm right here.
- Oh.
Until next time, Nelson,
fresh pain awaits.
(cackling)
- Pleasant, well
I see your point.
(soft instrumental music)
- Bring on my fiancee.